让我们回顾一下我们在这个特定讲座中涉及的一些主要概念。
Let’s recap some of the main concepts we have covered in this particular lecture.
我们想解释颜色的概念来自哪里，这是一个多步骤的过程。
We want to explain where the idea of color comes from and it’s a multi-step process.
这个过程的第一步是光源;那是发光的物体
The first step in the process is the illuminant; that is the object that emits light which
落到了现场。那个入射光我们称之为照度和它的种类
falls onto the scene. That incoming light we refer to as illuminance and it’s kind
频谱;它是波长的函数，我们用字母E表示它。那个光
of a spectrum; it is a function of the wavelength and we refer to it by the letter E. That light
落在一个物体上，物体的反射率也是一个功能波长，
falls onto an object, and the object has got a reflectance which is also a functional wavelength,
所以红色物体反射更多的红光和其他种类的光。一个蓝色物体会
so a red object reflects more red light and other sorts of light. A blue object would
反射更蓝光然后其他种类的光。离开物体的光我们
reflect more blue light then other kinds of light. The light that leaves the object we
“亮度”是指亮度，物体的亮度和亮度的光谱
refer to as the luminance, the luminance of the object, and the spectrum of the luminance
是照度，入射光和反射光谱的函数
is a function of the spectrum of the illuminance, the incoming light and the reflectance of
物体。那光线进入观察者的视线，
the object. That light enters the eye of an observer,
在观察者眼睛后面的观察者中有许多不同的观察者
and within the observer at the back of the observer’s eye are a number of different
光敏感细胞-它们有不同的反应，它们对不同部位有反应
light sensitive cells—they have different responses and they respond to different parts
光谱。这些锥细胞的响应用N表示，它是一个函数
of the spectrum. The response of theses cone cells is denoted by N and it is a function
兰达不同的锥细胞具有不同的Ns。整体反应
of lambda. The different cone cells have got different Ns. The overall response of the
锥形细胞是入射光光谱波长的积分
cone cell is the integral over the wavelength of the spectrum of the incoming light, the
物体的反射率，以及单个锥体细胞的响应。在锥体内
reflectance of the object, and the response of the individual cone cell. Within the cone
细胞通过化学反应将光子转换成行进的电脉冲
cell the photons are converted via a chemical reaction to electrical impulses which travel
通过观察者的视觉皮层，它们会产生我们的感觉
through to visual cortex of the observer, and they result in a sensation that we have
学会了与红字联系起来。我们有许多光源
learned to associate with the word red. There are many sources of light and we have
触及其中一些。白炽度是热物体可以接受的光
touched on some of these. Incandescence is the light admitted by hot objects that could
是钨灯泡的白热灯丝，也可能是太阳。其他来源
be the white hot filament of a tungsten light bulb or it could be the sun. Other sources
光是电子刺激，如在旧式阴极射线管中发生的那样，光线允许
of light are electron stimulation as occurs in old fashion cathode ray tubes, light admitting
二极管，紧凑型荧光灯管和其他气体放电管和激光器。每一个
diodes, compact fluorescent tubes and other gas discharged tubes and lasers. Each of these
具有不同的亮度光谱。光是电磁辐射的一种形式
has a different luminance spectrum. Light is a form of electromagnetic radiation and
这种辐射在波长方面有所不同。用我们的眼睛，我们只能看到它
this radiation varies in terms of its wavelength. With our eyes we are only able to see that
部分电磁波谱，但波长在400到700纳米之间
part of the electromagnetic spectrum, but with wavelengths between 400 and 700 nanometers
普通光源发出的光很多-尤其是太阳和白炽灯泡
a lot of light emitted by common light sources—particularly the sun and incandescent light bulbs—is
在光谱的红外线部分，虽然我们看不到
in the infra-red part of the spectrum, and although we can’t see
红外线，我们可以感受到它。我们可以把它感觉为热量。
infra-red we can feel it. We can sense it as heat.
在我们眼睛的视网膜中，我们有大量的光敏细胞：有
In the retina of our eyes we have a large number of light sensitive cells: there are
杆细胞和锥细胞。现在正是锥形细胞给我们带来了色觉。
rod cells and cone cells. Now it is the cone cells that give us our sense of color vision.
有三种不同类型的视锥细胞：对红色敏感的视锥细胞
There are three different types of cone cells: those that are sensitive to red, those that
对绿色敏感，对蓝色敏感。他们经常被提及
are sensitive to green and those that are sensitive to blue. Often times they are referred
作为短，中，长波长锥体。锥体有些重叠
to as the short, medium and long wavelength cones. The cones have somewhat overlapping
响应函数;特别是，红色和绿色锥体显着重叠。
response functions; in particular, the red and green cones are significantly overlapped.
我们有三种类型的锥体这一事实意味着我们被称为trichromats-we
The fact that we have three types of cones means that we are called trichromats—we
有三色视觉。并非所有动物都有三色视觉;大多数哺乳动物只有
have three-color vision. Not all animals have three-color vision; most mammals only have
双色视觉。我们称它们为重铬酸盐。许多其他动物都有四色视觉。
two-color vision. We call them dichromats. Many other animals have four-color vision.
我们称它们为四色，鸟类就是典型的例子。
We call them tetrachromats and birds are a typical example of that.
当我们制作相机时，我们借用了很多这些原理;我们有一个底层数组
When we create cameras, we borrow a lot of these principles; we have an underlying array
有机硅光电传感器，每个都对各种颜色敏感。
of silicone photo sensors and each of those are sensitive to a wide range of colors.
为了使它们对颜色敏感，我们在它们上面打印彩色滤光片，通常在a
To make them color sensitive we print color filters on top of them and generally in a
2乘2阵列我们称之为拜耳模式，因此每2乘2阵列包含两个
2 by 2 array which we refer to as the Bayer pattern, so each 2 by 2 array contains two
绿色滤镜和红色滤镜和蓝色滤镜。所以我们在硅胶中创造了一种类似物
green filters and a red filter and a blue filter. So we create in silicone an analogue
人眼中的颜色传感机制。
of the color sensing mechanism in the human eye.
如果我看一个具有特定颜色的物体，我会改变照明的强度
If I look at an object with a particular color and I change the intensity of the illumination
对象的外观会发生变化，这里我们看到对象的例子
the appearance of the object will change, and here we see examples of the object at
亮度为100％，75％，50％和0％。RGB值正在变化，但颜色却在变化
100%, 75%, 50% and 0% brightness. The RGB values are changing, but the color of the
对象本身并没有改变，所以我们想找到一种方法来解决颜色与强度的关系。
object itself does not change, so we want to find a way to disentangle color from intensity.
要映射我们称之为三刺激值的三个-即红色，绿色和蓝色
To map the three what we call tristimulus values—that is, the red, green and blue
将值转换为亮度值和两个颜色值-现在我们可以非常简单地执行此操作
value into a brightness value and two color values—now we can do this very simply by
将RGB值转换为我们称之为色度坐标的值，由下式表示
converting the RGB values to what we call chromaticity coordinates, indicated by the
小写r，g和b。现在这三个数字实际上是多余的。我可以计算任何
lower case r, g and b. Now these three numbers are actually redundant. I can compute any
其中一个给了另外两个，所以我们只需要使用其中两个，通常我们保留
one of them given the other two, so we only need to use two of them and typically we keep
只有R和G，这些数字在0和1之间变化。
only R and G, these numbers vary between zero and one.
因此，如果我们在水平轴上绘制一个图形，我们在垂直方向上有r坐标
So if we make a graph where on the horizontal axis we have the r coordinate, on the vertical
我们有g坐标，然后每个可能的颜色出现在这个三角形内
axis we have the g coordinate, then every possible color appears within this triangle
......纯红色出现在这里，纯绿色出现在这里，纯蓝色出现在这里，
… pure red appears here, pure green appears here, pure blue appears here,
并且任何颜色都不可能存在于蓝线上方。
and it is not possible for any colors to exist above the blue line.